-==http://www.1000fr.com== 謦灵风软影视论坛荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业用途
www.1000fr.com presents
福尔摩斯探案 之归来记
The Return of Sherlock Holmes
-=Keepfrds MNHD Team=- 校对: ptrpan
第四季 第四集
S4E04
威斯特里亚寓所
Wisteria Lodge
Scott Eccles先生
Mr. Scott Eccles.
哦 Garcia先生
Oh, Mr. Garcia.
很抱歉没能立刻认出你来
I'm sorry I did not recognize you at once.
我来帮您拿箱子吧
Please allow me to carry your case.
你真太客气了
That's very civil of you.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
真抱歉在这么一个天气里
I'm sorry if the weather
欢迎您的到来
has been unkind for your visit.
对你而言 天气也许不好
Unkind for you perhaps
但对我们英国人来说 你知道的
but we British, you know,
我们生命力顽强
we're hardy souls.
Surrey县特别有意思
The county of Surrey is particularly interesting
我盼望着向您展示
I'm looking forward to showing you
我收藏的所有老地图
my entire collection of old maps.
我有Moore和Ogelby的作品
I mean there's Moore and Ogelby.
我带来了一两张可以给你看看
I got one or two here I can show you.
他以前画的
He used to draw.
[西班牙文]
[Speaking Spanish]
这是你家么
This is your house is it?
是的 请进
Yes. Please.
别客气
Your welcome.
这里很不错
It's very nice.
华生  我们必须认为
I suppose Watson we must look upon you
你是一名作家
as a man of letters.
你怎么解释“怪诞”一词的
How do you define the word 'grotesque'?
怪诞
Grotesque.
奇怪-不同寻常
Strange-remarkable.
不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no.
肯定不只是那样
Surely there's more to it than that.
还有一些潜在含义
Some underlying suggestion
比如悲惨或者恐怖的事情
of a tragic or terrible.
如果你回想一下那些事件
If you cast your mind back to those narratives
你那些长期折磨
with which you've inflicted
公众的文章
a long-suffering public,
你会发现“怪诞”一词如此频繁地
you will see how often the word 'grotesque'
同犯罪结合在一起
has deepened into the criminal.
我想
I suppose
红发会事件
the affair of the redheaded men
开头相当怪诞
was grotesque enough at the outset.
五个桔核事件
Most grotesque affair
一直很怪诞
of the five orange pips.
是的 那直接引出一宗谋杀案
Yes, which led straight to a murderous conspiracy.
现在这个词...让我警惕
Now the word puts me on the alert.
电报里有这个词么
Have you it there?
我遇到一件难以置信
I've just had the most incredible
和怪诞之事
and grotesque experience.
我可以向您求教么 Scott Eccles
May I consult you Scott Eccles?
查林十字街邮局
Post-Office, Charring Cross.
男的还是女的
A man or woman?
男的
A man.
女人不会发这种预付了回电费的电报
No woman would send a reply-paid telegram.
她会直接上门来的
She would have come.
你要见他么
Will you see him?
哦 我亲爱的华生
Oh my dear Watson,
你知道自从我们关押了 卡鲁塞斯上校之后
you know how bored I've been
我有多无聊么
since we locked up Colonel Carruthers.
生活平淡
Life is commonplace
报纸枯燥无味
the newspapers are sterile
冒险和罗曼史似乎从这个罪恶的世上
audacity and romance seem to have passed forever
永远消失了
from the criminal world.
我当然要见他
Of course I'll see him.
如果我没弄错的话 这位就是我们的委托人
Unless I'm very much mistaken, this is our client.
福尔摩斯先生么?
Mr. Holmes?
谢谢你 Hudson太太
Thank you, Mrs. Hudson.
-您是福尔摩斯先生么? -是的
Well are you Mr. Holmes? --Certainly.
是的 福尔摩斯先生
Yes, Mr. Holmes,
我遇到了一件极奇怪
I have just had a most singular
极不愉快的事
and unpleasant experience.
我有生以来还从未有过这样的遭遇
No way in my life have I been subject to...
真是奇耻大辱
to such embarrassment
难以容忍
and been placed in such a position.
请坐 Scott Eccles先生
Please sit down, Mr. Scott Eccles,
这位是我的朋友和同事 华生医生
my friend and colleague Doctor Watson.
首先 请问
In the first place, my I ask,
你为什么要来找我
why you have came to me at all?
嗯 先生 这件事看来
Well, sir, it didn't appear
和警察无关
to be a matter which concerned the police,
但是 等你听完这件事
yet,when you've heard the facts,
你肯定同意
you must admit
我不能就这么算了
I couldn't just leave it where it was.
而对于私家侦探
Now the private detectives
你们这一类人呢
they are a class with whom I'm absolutely,
我不是很感兴趣
I have no sympathy.
坐下 Scott Eccles先生
Sit, Mr. Scott Eccles.
虽然如此
Nonetheless,
我久仰您的大名
having heard your name...
-华生 -我决定...
-Watson! -I decided...
其次
Now in the second place,
为什么你不立刻就来?
why did you not come to me at once?
什么意思
What do you mean?
现在已经2点15分了
Well it is now a quarter-past two.
你的电报是1点发的
Your telegram was dispatched about one.
瞧您这身装扮
No one could glance at your toilet and attire
就会知道您是在
without seeing that your disturbance dates
起床的时候遇上麻烦的
from the moment of your waking.
是这样的 福尔摩斯先生
But you're right, Mr. Holmes.
我从没想过要梳洗一下
Yet I never gave a thought to my toilet.
我是如此急于逃离那座房子
I was only too glad to get out of such a house.
哦 不用了 谢谢你
Oh no, no thank you.
你看 在我来这之前
You see but I have been running round
我四处打听情况
making inquiries before I came here.
我打电话给房屋管理处 你知道的  是的
I called the house agents, you know, oh yes,
是的 但他们说... 他们说
yes, and they said... they said
Garcia先生的房租已经付过了
that Mr. Garcia's rent was paid up all right
还说威斯特里亚寓所里一切正常
and that everything was in order in Wisteria Lodge.
冷静 冷静  Eccles先生
Then they you'll come, come, sir Eccles.
你和我的朋友华生一样
You know you're like my friend, Watson,
都有个坏习惯 叙述事情
who has the bad habit of telling his stories
老是头尾颠倒
wrong end foremost.
现在 请你...请你 整理一下思路
Now please, please arrange your thoughts
按顺序告诉我
and let me know, in their due sequence,
到底发生了什么事
exactly what those events are,
什么事让你就这样跑出来
which have sent you out
头也不梳脸也不刮
unbrushed and unkempt,
靴子和背心的口子也没扣好
with your dress boots and waistcoat buttoned awry,
就这样来寻求建议和帮助
in search of advice and assistance.
我是一个单身汉
Well I'm a bachelor
由于喜欢社交
and being of a sociable turn
我结识了一大帮朋友
I cultivate a large number of friends.
在最近的一次聚会上
At the table of one of them recently,
我认识了一位名叫Garcia的年轻人
I met a young fellow named Garcia,
一个令人愉快的家伙
a pleasant chap
有西班牙血统
of Spanish decent,
和西班牙大使馆有些联系
connected in some way with the Embassy.
我们发现彼此对测绘地图有共同的兴趣爱好
We discovered a common interest in cartography
或者我是这么认为的
or so I thought.
我们研究老地图
That's the study of old maps.
我们计划追寻五十年前
The plan was to retrace Surrey as Thomas Mould
Thomas Mould绘制地图的路线
engraved it some fifty years ago.
当我昨晚到达的时候
Well as soon as I arrived yesterday evening
我发觉那里的气氛
I knew something was wrong.
有些不对劲
The atmosphere of the place,
屋子里昏暗陈旧
the house was tumbledown,
压抑的很
depressing.
Garcia告诉我说他有个很棒的厨子
Garcia told me he had a wonderful cook,
那人有一半西班牙血统 是他在旅途中认识的
a half breed he had picked up on his travels
但是那天的晚餐
but the dinner,
如此糟糕
well it was so ill-prepared
服务很不周到
and served with such bad grace
饭菜难以下咽
that it was barely edible.
我向你保证那天晚上
I can assure you that there were many times
有好几次
in the course of the evening
我真想找个借口离开
I wished I could have invented some excuse to leave.
你说什么
What did you say?
房间非常棒
Well the rooms is fascinating.
John Rogglbe
John Rogglbe.
那么很热门咯
Across the heat then?
不仅热门 伙计 可以说是风靡全郡
Wasn't just heat lad, it was all over the county.
你没有什么不舒服吧
I tell you, you feeling all right?
没有
Yes.
对不起
Sorry.
嘿  嘿
Please, Please.
给客人再上点酒
Some more wine for our guest.
好的
Yes.
[西班牙文]
[Speaking Spanish]
还有客人要来么
Are we expecting company?
可以的话 我还想喝点那个
I would like a drink of that if it's possible.
他没有对字条上的内容
And he made no remark
说些什么吗?
as to the contents of the note?
没有
None.
但从那时起
But for that moment
他收起了谈话时的所有伪装
he gave up all pretence at conversation.
就坐在那儿
He just sat there
不停地抽着雪茄
smoking these endless cigarettes.
大概11点的时候 我很高兴可以去睡觉了
About eleven I was glad to go to bed.
2小时以后
Two hours later
他来到我房间里
he looked in at my door.
你有摇铃叫我么
Did you ring?
我有摇铃么?
Did I ring?
哦 别起来 现在快1点了
Awe, please don't wake up it's nearly one o'clock.
继续睡吧
Please go back to sleep.
晚安
Good night.
接下来就到最关键的部分了
And now I come to the amazing part of my tale.
当我醒来的时候 天已经大亮了
When I woke it was broad daylight,
快9点了
nearly nine.
我特别交待他们 要在8点钟叫醒我
I had particularly asked to be called at eight,
所以我很震惊
so I was very much astonished
怎能如此健忘
at this forgetfulness.
我说有人在吗
I say is anybody here?
我想要点热水
I'd like some hot water.
我摇铃叫仆人
I rang for the servant.
没有回应
There was no response.
有人吗
Somebody?
我说有人服务没
I say is there a servant available.
真该死
This is damnable.
我把房间挨个找了一遍
I went from room to room,
都是空的
all were deserted.
主人房也一样
Even my host room,
床铺没人睡过
the bed had never been slept in.
外国主人
Foreign host,
外国仆人
foreign footman,
外国厨子
foreign cook,
在晚上全消失了
all vanished in the night.
您的经历
Your experience is,
就我看来
so far as I know,
非常奇特
perfectly unique.
还有什么别的情况么
Now what else can you tell me?
恩 我异常愤怒
Well, I was furious.
我收拾了行李
I packed my bags
摔上大门
and I banged the front door behind me
出发去Esher了
and I set out for Esher.
后来我给 Allan Brothers'地产经纪
Then I called at Allan Brothers',
打电话
the land agents,
我发现这栋别墅
and found it was from them
是向他们租来的
that the villa had been rented.
租的?
Rented?
你看
Well you see
我不敢相信
I couldn't believe
他们消失了
that they had gone
就为了作弄我
simply to make a fool of me.
我想他们肯定是想赖租金
I thought, you know, it must be the rent
但我错了
but I was wrong.
房屋经纪人感谢我的提醒
See the agent thanked me for my warning
并告诉我说租金已经预付了
but said that the rent had been paid in advance.
我猜也许是大使馆付的
By the Spanish embassy I imagine?
我给西班牙大使馆打电话
I called at the Spanish embassy.
他们不认识这些人
The man is unknown to them.
我也问了把他们介绍给我认识的朋友
I also asked my friend who introduced us
他和我一样不了解他们
and he seemed to know less about Garcia than I did.
现在 这座房子
Now, this house,
威斯特里亚公寓
Wisteria Lodge,
我想它是否和你离开时一样
I wonder if it's still as you left it.
想什么呢 华生
What's troubling you, Watson?
厄
Huh?
恐怕等我们到那儿的时候
Well I fear some mundane explanation of the events
也许会发现原因其实很简单
may await us upon our arrival.
有可能
It's possible.
感谢我们的好运气
We can thank our lucky fate,
把我们从百无聊赖中
which will rescue us for a few hours
拯救出来几个小时
from the insufferable fatigues of idleness.
这位先生推荐村里的公牛旅馆
This gentleman recommends The Bull in the village,
我们可以在那里过夜
that's if we're to stay overnight.
我问他是否认识Garcia
I asked him if he knew Garcia
或者他的仆人
or his servants.
他认识么?
Did he?
不认识
No.
外边没有什么特别的
Nothing unusual about the outside.
让我们看里面的情况
Let's see what the interior holds for us.
我希望我们不会因非法侵入
I don't suppose we could be charged
而被起诉
with housebreaking can we?
怎么这么乱七八糟的 也不收拾
Who on earth could leave such a mess?
的确如此
Yes indeed.
到屋子里四处看看 华生
Take a glance around the house, Watson.
福尔摩斯先生么?
Mr. Holmes?
欢迎您来威斯特里亚公寓 福尔摩斯先生
Welcome to Wisteria Lodge, Mr. Holmes.
我是Surrey 警队的Baynes警长
Inspector Baynes of the Surrey Constabulary.
这位是Downing警官
This is Constable Downing.
您是住在李街Popham公馆的
And you are Mr. John Scott Eccles
John Scott Eccles 先生么
of Popham House,Lee?
是的
I am.
Scott Eccles先生
Mr. Scott Eccles
我们跟了您一个上午了
we've been following you about all the morning.
我想您是通过电报找到他的吧
You traced him through his telegram, I presume?
没错 福尔摩斯先生
Exactly, Mr. Holmes.
我们在查林十字街邮局发现了他的踪迹
We picked up the scent at Charring Cross Post-Office.
你想干什么
But what'd you want?
为什么跟踪我
And why did you follow me?
我们想要您一份证词 Scott Eccles先生
We wish a statement, Mr. Scott Eccles,
关于住在Esher附近
as to the events which led up to the death
威斯特里亚寓所的
of Mr. Aloysius Garcia,
Aloysius Garcia先生死亡事件的证词
of Wisteria Lodge,near Esher.
你说死亡?
Dead did you say?
是的先生 他死了
Oh yes sir, he is dead.
是的
Yes.
怎么死的
But how?
意外么?
An accident?
谋杀 先生 如果世界上发生过谋杀的话
Murder, sir, if ever there was one on earth.
哦 上帝啊
Good God!
这太可怕了
This is awful!
您不会认为我是嫌疑犯吧
You don't mean that I'm suspected?
先生 我们在死者身上
Well, sir, you're note was found
发现了您写的字条
on the dead man's body
上面说
and from it we learned
你打算昨晚上
that you had planned to stay here
在这里过夜
in this house last night.
是这样的
So I did.
你在这过夜了 是么
Oh, you did, did you?
等一下
Wait.
Baynes 我想
Baynes, I mean surely
你要的只是一份简单的证词吧
all you need is a simple statement.
是的 福尔摩斯先生 但是我有责任
Yes, Mr. Holmes, but it is my duty
提醒Scott Eccles先生
to warn Mr. Scott Eccles
这份证词将作为呈堂证供
that it may be used against him.
这位是我的同伴 华生医生
Awe, this is my fellow colleague, Dr. Watson,
Baynes警长
Inspector Baynes.
-是的 当然 -医生 来一下
-Yes of course. -Doctor your attention.
Scott Eccles 先生 您看上去
Mr. Scott Eccles you look as if
好像需要喝点酒吧
you could do with a drink.
我在书房发现了些白兰地 如果你想...
I found some brandy in the library if you think...
谢谢你
Thank you.
[西班牙文]
[Speaking Spanish]
我向您保证警长
Well I can assure you, Inspector that, you know,
我说的每个字都是真的
every word I've said it is the truth.
我一定要说的是 Scott Eccles先生
I'm bound to say, Mr. Scott Eccles,
您说的每件事
that everything you've said
和我们注意到的事实
does agree with the facts
都完全一致
as they've come to our notice.
比如说 晚餐时送来的字条
For example, the note that arrived during dinner.
Scott Eccles先生 这张字条后来怎么了
Mr. Scott Eccles what became of the note?
Garcia 把它揉成一团
Well, Garcia rolled it up
扔到火里去了
and threw it in the fire.
对此你有什么要说的么  Baynes先生
What do you say to that, Baynes?
这是个带栅栏的壁炉 福尔摩斯先生
It was a dog-grate, Mr. Holmes,
他扔过头了
he over pitched it.
我在炉子后面找到了 这张没有烧着的字条
I found this unburned of the back.
您一定把房子搜查得
You must have made a very careful
十分仔细
examination of the house
才能找到这么小的纸条
to find a single pellet of paper.
哦 是的 福尔摩斯先生
Oh, I did, Mr. Holmes, I did.
这正是我工作作风
It's my way.
字条是写在一张普通的乳黄色
The note is written on ordinary cream-laid paper
带水印的纸上
with a watermark.
它有四分之一张纸那么大
It's a quarter-sheet.
用短刃剪刀 剪了两下
The paper's cut off in two snips
剪下来的
with a short-bladed scissors.
折叠两次后
It's been folded twice
用红色的蜡封口
and sealed with scarlet wax.
字条是送给
It's addressed to
威斯特里亚公寓的Garcia先生
Mr. Garcia, Wisteria Lodge
上面写着
and it says
"我们自己的颜色 绿和白"
Our own colors, green and white.
"绿色开"
Green open,
"白色关"
white shut.
"主楼梯"
Main stairs,
"第一个走廊"
first corridor,
"右边第七"
seventh right,
"绿粗呢"
green baize.
"祝成功"
Godspeed.
署名"D"
D.
是女人的笔迹
It's in a woman's writing,
笔头非常尖
done with a very sharp-pointed pen,
但是地址是用不同的笔写的
but the address is either done with a different pen
或者是别人写的
or by someone else
因为字迹更粗重
because it's thicker and bolder,
你看 福尔摩斯先生
as you may see, Mr. Holmes.
这是一张不同寻常的字条
It's a remarkable note.
我必须得祝贺您
I really must congratulate you
注意到了细节
on your attention to detail.
但是还要补充一些
There are a few trifling points
小细节
which might perhaps be added.
字条是用袖口封口的
The seal is a sleeve-link
还会有其他什么东西是这样的形状呢
what else is of such a shape?
剪刀是弯头的指甲剪
The scissors were bent nail scissors.
虽然剪的两下都不长
Short as the two snips are,
你还是能清楚地看到
you can distinctly see
每一刀都有一样略弯的曲线
the same slight curve in each.
我还以为已找到了全部线索了 福尔摩斯先生
I thought I had squeezed it dry, Mr. Holmes,
但显然我还是漏掉了一些东西
but I see there was some still left over after all.
我得说
I'm bound to say
我并不太明白纸条的意思
that I make nothing of the note
但我知道有人在搞名堂
except that there's something's on hand,
这件事照例
and a woman, as usual,
还牵涉到一个女人
is at the bottom of it.
警长 我很高兴你找到了这张纸条
I'm very glad you found the note, Inspector,
因为它证明了我说的话
because it collaborates my story.
但是 你知道 我要说的是
But, you know, I do beg to point out
我还不知道
that I haven't yet heard
Garcia先生发生了什么事
what has happened to Mr. Garcia,
或者他家里发生了什么事
or what has become of his household.
Garcia先生么 很容易回答
As for Mr. Garcia, that's easily answered.
今天早上发现他死在
He was found dead
Oxshott公有地上
on Oxshott Common this morning.
他的脑袋被沙袋或类似的东西
His head had been beaten to a pulp by a sandbag
打成了肉酱
or some such object,
不仅是打破了 简直是稀巴烂
which had crushed rather than wounded.
很明显 他最初
Apparently he'd been
是被人从后面袭击的
first struck down from behind,
但是凶手在他死后
but his assailant went on beating him
还打了很久
long after he was dead.
这是一次非常残暴的袭击
It was a very furious assault.
可以说是我们见过的
Awe, I mean this activity that we saw
最严重的一次行凶了
has to be approached at the highest.
发现脚印或其他犯罪线索了么
Were there any footsteps or clues as tothe criminal?
没有 还没有
No, no, as yet.
Garcia 被抢劫了么?
Had Garcia been robbed?
没有
No.
没有抢劫的迹象
No sign of robbery.
我们的租户好像
Well our tenants seem to have left
什么东西也没有留下
little or nothing behind them.
除了衣服
Apart from the clothes,
几个烟斗 几本小说
some pipes, a few novels,
其中有两本是西班牙文的
two of them in Spanish.
其中一把不见了
One of them is missing.
是的
Yeah.
可以认为'G'代表Garcia
We might assume the 'G' stands for Garcia.
也许是祖传的
Family heirloom perhaps.
另一把枪不在死者身上
The other was not on the body
在附近也没有找到
nor has it been found in the vicinity
但我的人还在寻找
though my men are still looking.
你想看看房子周围么
Do you wish to look around the house?
稍稍看一下
A brief look.
福尔摩斯!
Holmes!
华生!
Watson!
看见什么了
What have you seen?
就像个魔鬼
Could have been the devil for all I know.
瞪着眼睛从窗外朝里看
Staring eyes at the window.
有黑人特征 像是黑白混血儿
Negroid features, mulatto like.
穿过空地跑了
It's got away across the field.
也许这样也好
Maybe just as well
我想我可能打不过他
I don't think I could have laid hands on him.
哦 看看这个
Awe, look at this.
如果他的身材和脚般配的话
If he is all the same scale as his foot
他一定是个巨人
then he is certainly a giant.
不管他是谁 他想干嘛
Well whoever he was, whatever he wanted
目前他逃走了
he's gone for the present,
我们要关心更重要的事
and we have more important things to attend to.
Downing 你留下
Downing, you stay here.
诸位请跟我到局里一趟
And you sir shall come to the station with me.
-好的 先生 -我要做份笔录
-Yes sir. -And let me have a written statement.
是的 我立刻就来
Yes certainly I'd come at once.
我希望您不介意
I hope you don't my
我们一起合作 警长
collaborating with you Inspector.
我很荣幸 福尔摩斯先生
I'd be honored, Mr. Holmes.
荣幸之至
I'd be honored.
警长 有没有线索证明
Inspector, is there any clue
那人准确的死亡时间么
as to the exact hour of the man's death?
一点钟
One o'clock.
那时候在下雨
It rained about that time
死亡肯定在下雨之前
and the death certainly occurred before the rain.
不 不 不
No. No, no.
那绝对不可能 Baynes先生
That's perfectly impossible, Mr. Baynes.
不 不 他的声音很特殊
No, no, his voice is very unmistakable.
我发誓
I could swear to it
那个时候在我房间里和我说话的人
that it was he who addressed me in my room
就是他
at that very hour.
他和我说话 你知道
Well he spoke to me, you know,
他有那种可笑的口音
in that funny accent of his.
他说就要1点了
He said he's it's nearly one o'clock.
很好 但是我们要分清不太可能
Remarkable but we must not confuse the unlikely
和绝不可能
with the impossible.
他什么意思
What does he mean of that?
显然那房子里的人很古怪
Certainly some strange people occupy that house,
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes.
有一个已经死了
One of them is dead.
是他的同伴
Did some of his companions
跟着他然后杀了他么?
follow him and murder him?
如果是这样的话 我们会在被监视的每个港口抓到他们
If so, we should have them for every port is watched
但我不这么认为 福尔摩斯先生
but my views are different, Mr. Holmes.
是的先生 我有不同的看法
Yes sir, my views are very different.
你很有一套
You have a theory?
我要自己干 福尔摩斯先生
And I'll work it myself, Mr. Holmes.
你已经名闻天下了
Your name is already made,
我还在努力中
I have yet to make mine
我将来会说
and I shall like to be able to say afterwards,
我没有依靠你的帮助 解决了这个案子
that I solved it without your help.
那么你走你的阳光道
Then you do follow your path
我走我的独木桥
and I will follow mine.
再见 Scott Eccles先生
Goodbye, Mr. Scott Eccles.
再见 福尔摩斯先生
Goodbye, Mr. Holmes.
Scott Eccles
Scott Eccles.
我们研究下字条吧
Let us consider this note.
这牵涉到一位女士么?
Is there a woman involved?
嫉妒的丈夫?
A jealous husband?
上帝保佑
Godspeed.
上帝保佑D  她会成为我们的引路人
Godspeed D, that must be our guide.
这个男子是个西班牙人
The man was a Spaniard
我猜 'D'代表Delores
I suggest that the 'D' stands for Delores.
它是常用的西班牙妇女的名字
It's a common female name in Spain.
西班牙人之间会用西班牙文通信的
A Spaniard would write to a Spaniard in Spanish,
华生
Watson.
[西班牙文]
[Speaking Spanish]
Henderson庄园...High Gable... George Ffolliott
Henderson, High Gable, George Ffolliott.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes?
看看我发现了什么
Look what I've found.
从灌木丛里
In the bush.
好极了
Excellent.
非常抱歉
I'm terribly sorry.
我好像…
I've seemed to have...
[西班牙文]
[speaking Spanish]
你侵入了我们的住所
You are trespassing.
非常抱歉 我迷路了
I'm terribly sorry. I've seemed to have lost my direction.
你们老是这么好奇…
Is it your custom to wonder...
啊 Rayfield医生
Awe, Doctor Rayfield,
我的朋友和制图伙伴
my friend and fellow cartographer.
是的
Yes indeed.
你那么认真地
You were so engrossed
找寻一条通往
in trying to chase the bridal path
已消失的圣玛丽村的结婚路线
to a now vanished Hamlet of Obligor St Mary
因此我们分开了
that we mislaid each other.
由于来见Henderson先生有点晚了 我想
And since we're late for Mr. Henderson, I thought,
很高兴你找到这儿了
I'm so glad you found your way here.
我很抱歉
Well I very much regret that
Henderson先生今天很忙不能见您
Mr. Henderson is too busy to see you today.
不 Lucas
No Lucas,
我要见他们
I will see them.
先生们
Gentlemen.
我们拜访的目的是
The purpose of our visit
想咨询一下High Gable的历史
is to inquire into the history of High Gable,
我们相信英国内战以来
which we believe has an
这里有一段迷人
intriguing and blood fested past.
但充满血雨腥风的过去
Since the days of the English civil war.
对此我一无所知
I would have no knowledge of that.
我只是个新近的侵略者
I'm only a recent invader.
但是书房里可能会有些过去的资料
But there are local records in the library.
这房子里没有发现
There are no records of any past
任何过去的纪录
found in this house.
我明白了
I see.
那么我不再打扰你了
Then I will detain you no more.
日安
Good day.
我以为你去伦敦了
I thought you were in London.
只是上午在那里
For the morning only.
由于和往常一样
Well with your usual reluctance
你不愿意告诉我你的想法
to confide your thoughts to me
我分析了一下情况
I exercised my own mind in the matter.
你的名单上圈了两个名字
You'd circled two names on your list,
Henderson 和 High Gable
Henderson and High Gable.
恩 其他的人
Well the others are,
可以说 都是有名望的人
per say, respectable people.
和浪漫史沾不上边
Far aloof from romance
除了这位 Henderson
but this man, Henderson,
是一位特别的人物
but he's a very singular creation.
的确如此
Yes indeed.
你也可能注意到了
As you may have noticed...
我不喝
no tea for me...
屋子有两翼
the house is double winged.
一边住着仆人 另一边住着主人
One side the servants the other side the family.
中间只有一扇连接的门
There is one single connecting door
用来给Henderson家人上菜
for the Henderson family meals.
我相信在我们拜访的如此短暂的时间里
I'm sure you couldn't have observed all that
你不可能注意到这些的 福尔摩斯
in the short time we there, Holmes.
我通过流言蜚语和被解雇的仆人
I was looking for evidence in gossip
寻找证据
and discharged servants
我很幸运地找到一位
and I was lucky to enough to find one
他被专横的
who had been sacked
主人Henderson解雇了
by his imperious master Henderson
并且饱受他的暴虐之苦
and a victim of violent temper.
我们的Henderson小姐们
Now the Henderson girls,
就是我们遇见过的那两位
who we encountered,
有一位家庭教师
have a governess.
Burnet小姐 一位英国女士
A Miss Burnet, an English woman.
很奇怪的是
Here is the very singular fact.
谋杀案之后
She has not been seen
她再也没出现过
since the night of the murder.
她彻底消失了
She has utterly vanished.
我见过她
I've seen her.
肯定是
Of course,
我见过她 她还活着
I've seen her and she is alive.
我看见她站在High Gable的窗户前
I saw her at the window at High Gable.
上帝啊 被囚禁了
My God a prisoner.
那可怕的女孩们袭击我的时候
She slipped my mind.
我看见她了
The moment those awful girls descended upon me.
她还活着 我见到她了
She is alive, I've seen her.
那就是我看见和追过的那个男人
That's the man I saw and chased.
Baynes抓错人了
Baynes has arrested the wrong man.
华生 快点 我们必须阻止他
Now Watson, quickly, we must stop him.
他是凶手么?
Is he the murderer?
他杀了西班牙人吗?
Did he kill a Spaniard?
你们在哪里抓到他的
Where did you capture him?
这人是受害者的厨子
This man is the murdered man's cook
他在案发当晚失踪了
who disappeared on the night of the crime.
我们相信房子里
We believe there were valuables
存有贵重物品
left in the house
这就是引出了
and that there abstraction
作案动机
was the motive.
有人看见他曾经
The man had been seen
出现在屋子周围
in the vicinity of the house once before.
第二次
The second time,
抓牢他 Higgins
subdue him Higgins.
第二次 我们留守的人抓到他了
The second time we let a man escape for him
在把他送交地方官之前
we shall be applying for remand
我们要申请遣送
when the prisoner's brought before the magistrate.
目前就这些情况 先生们
That will be all for now, gentlemen.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
是在路上吗
Was it on the way?
你们在哪里抓到他的
Where did you capture him?
Baynes
Baynes?
我不认为你走对路了
I am not convinced that you're on the right line.
福尔摩斯先生 不想你错的太离谱
Mr. Holmes doesn't want you to commit yourself too far
除非你有确凿把握
unless you're sure.
哦 你们真是好人
Oh, you're very kind gentlemen
但我们有协议
but we did agree
各行其事 对么
to work on our own lines didn't we?
这就是我所做的
And that's what I'm doing.
欢迎你们来我的新闻发布会
You're welcome always to my news.
这家伙壮得像匹拉车的马
This fellow is as strong as a carthorse
和魔鬼一样凶猛
and fierce as the devil.
在被制服之前
He nearly bit off Constable Downing's thumb
他几乎咬掉了Downing警官的大拇指
before they managed to master him.
他几乎不会说英语
He speaks hardly any English
除了咕哝声 我们从他嘴里问不出什么
and we can get nothing out of him but grunts.
你认为你有证据
And you think that you have evidence
证明他杀了他的雇主
that he murdered his late master?
我没这么说 福尔摩斯先生
I didn't say so, Mr. Holmes.
我没这么说
I didn't say so.
我们都有自己的小窍门
We all have our own little ways.
你走你的阳光道
You will go yours
我走我的独木桥
and I will go mine.
那就是协议
That was the agreement.
就这么办吧
So be it.
我想Baynes终究会摔个大跟头
I think Baynes is riding for the fall.
我同意你的观点
I would have to agree with you there.
你知道我们面临的困难 华生
You appreciate our difficulty, Watson.
我们没有申请保释的理由
There's nothing upon which we can apply for a warrant.
在我们尊敬的警长
And with our worthy Inspector
把嫌犯抓到之后
making his arrests
地方官只会认为
our theory would seem fantastic
我们的推理是荒谬的
if laid before the magistrate.
你还是认为那位女士有生命危险么
Yet you think the lady's in danger of her life?
是的
Yes.
我确信这一点 华生
I'm sure of it Watson,
我们得靠自己
therefore we must take
来伸张正义了
the law into our own hands.
左边最上面
Top left bay.
我们可以从外屋进去
We could reach it from that outhouse.
快来
Come.
他们往火车站去了
They're heading for the station.
我们跟着马车去伦敦
We'll follow the coach to London.
好的
Right.
停下火车
Stop the train.
停下
Stop it.
为什么会这样 福尔摩斯先生
Why, Mr. Holmes,
你给了我所有我想要的证据
you have given me the very evidence I wanted.
我们一开始是站在同一起跑线上的
We were both on the same scent from the start.
你也在追查Henderson么
Were you after Henderson too?
是这样的 你先到那里
Quite so well, you first
后来 华生医生
and then Doctor Watson here
爬过High Gable的树篱笆
came crawling through the under growth
也来了
at High Gable.
那时候我正在一棵大树上观察你们呢
I was up a tree observing you both.
问题的关键是
It was just a question
谁先拿到证据
of who got the evidence first.
你为什么要抓那个混血儿?
Why did you arrest the mulatto?
我相信这位自称Henderson的人
Well I was sure that Henderson, as he calls himself,
发觉自己受怀疑了
felt he was suspected
他在认为自己仍处于危险中时
and he would make no move
是不会采取任何行动的
so long as he thought he was in danger
所以我故意抓错人
so I arrested the wrong man.
知道吗 警官
You know you will rise high
你一定会步步高升的
in your profession Inspector.
你颇具警察的本能和直觉
You have instinct and intuition.
多谢夸奖 福尔摩斯先生
Thank you, Mr. Holmes,
但是没有Burnet小姐的证词
but we can't arrest
我们不能实行抓捕
without Miss Burnet's evidence can we?
哦 她过一会儿就可以告诉你
Oh she'll be able to give you that in a moment
告诉我Henderson到底是谁
but tell me who is this man Henderson?
他是Don Murillo
He's Don Murillo,
也叫圣佩德罗之虎
known as the Tiger of San Pedro.
中美洲最危险的人之一
One of the most dangerous men out of Central America.
哦 是的
Oh indeed.
最残酷和嗜血的暴君
Most elude and blood thirsty tyrant.
他对一个善良的民族施加
Who imposed his earliest vices
残暴的统治长达12年之久
upon a caring people for almost twelve years.
是不是圣佩德罗的绿白旗
Was it the San Pedro colors green and white
提示了你
that first put you onto it?
是的 我还去了趟伦敦
That and my visit to London
拜访了外交部里的西班牙大使
to the Spanish embassy in the foreign office.
还是您来说吧 这是您的案子 警长
Now please this is your case, Inspector.
五年前
Five years ago
爆发了反对这位暴君的起义
there was a rising against the tyrant
当人们冲进Murillo的宫殿的时候 发现已经人去楼空了
but it was an empty palace they stormed on Murillo,
他的秘书
his secretary,
两个孩子 还有一切财物
two children and all the wealth
都用船运走了
had escaped by ship
并且从此
and from that moment
他们从地球上消失了
they disappeared from the face of the earth.
他的新身份
His identity has been a subject
成为欧洲报纸常谈论的题材
of constant comment in the European press.
我们一年前发现了他
We discovered him a year ago.
Burnet小姐
Miss Burnet?
你怎么会牵扯进来的 Burnet小姐
How came you into this matter Miss Burnet?
一位英国女士竟卷入这样一宗谋杀案
An English lady in such a murderous affair.
因为这世界上
Because there is no other way in the world
找不到另一种方式来伸张正义
by which justice can be gained.
多年前圣佩德罗血流成河的时候
What does the law of England care about
或在这个人用船偷运走我们的财富的时候
the rivers of blood shed so many years ago in San Pedro
英国法律起到了什么用呢
or the shipload of treasure that this man has stolen from us?
对于你们而言
To you
那些就像是发生在其他星球上的罪行
they're like crimes committed on some other planet.
但我们却了解
We know.
我真正的名字叫Signora Victor Durando
My real name is Signora Victor Durando.
我丈夫是圣佩德罗驻伦敦的大使
My husband was the minister of San Pedro in London.
我们在那里结识并结婚
He met and married me there.
他是世上少有的品格高尚的人
A nobler man never lived upon the earth.
不幸的是 Murillo觉得我丈夫对他不忠
Unhappily, Murillo heard of his exodus
找了些托辞把他召回国
and recalled him on some pretext,
并枪杀了他
and shot him
由于...
by a stroke of...
...有预感
of premonition.
我丈夫拒绝带我一起回国
My husband had refused to take me with him.
后来这个魔鬼垮台了
Then came the downfall of the monster.
他像你们说的那样逃走了
He escaped as you have described.
但是许多生命被他毁了
But the many whose lives he had ruined,
许多人的挚爱在他手里
whose loved ones had suffered torture
受尽折磨而死去
and death at his hands,
他们不会就此罢休的
would not let the matter rest.
我们结成一个团体
We banded ourselves into a society,
任务一天没完成
which should never be dissolved
我们一天不解散
until the work was done.
我的任务是混进他家
It was my part to attach myself to his household
通知其他人他的动向
and keep the others in touch with his movements.
我要保住家庭女教师的职位
I secured the position as governess.
[西班牙文]
[Speaking Spanish]
他根本不知道
He little knew that the woman
每天吃饭时面对的女人
who faced him at every meal
她的丈夫被他迫不及待地杀害了
was the woman whose husband he had hurried to eternity.
我向他微笑
I smiled on him,
教育他的孩子
did my duty to his children,
等待机会
and bided my time.
在巴黎我们试过一次 但失败了
An attempt was made in Paris and failed.
他带着我们在欧洲东拐西绕
We zigzagged here and there swiftly over Europe
甩掉了追踪者
to throw off our pursuers
最后回到 High Gable
and finally returned to High Gable.
Garcia和他的两位忠实伙伴
Garcia had been waiting there for nearly a year
在这里等了近一年了
with two trusted companions,
大家心中燃着报仇的火焰
all fired with the same reasons for revenge.
Garcia是谁
Who was Garcia?
Fernando Garcia的儿子
The son of Fernando Garcia.
圣佩德罗最高的神职官之一
One of the former highest dignitaries of San Pedro
他也被杀害了
who was murdered...
像你丈夫一样
like your husband.
你送来的字条
This note you sent,
你说被拦截了
you say it was intercepted.
在白天
During the day
Murillo非常小心
Murillo took every precaution
没有Lucas陪伴
and never went outside
从不出门
without his satellite Lucas.
甚至在夜里他也很警惕
Even at night the man was forever on the alert
常常变换房间
and continually changed his room.
我们约定
We had arranged
我给 Garcia送去最后的指示
that I would send Garcia final instructions.
然后把门打开
The doors would be opened
并在面朝大路的窗户前
and the signal of a green or white light
点上绿色
in a window,
或白色的灯
which faced the drive,
说明一切顺利
was to give notice if all was safe
或者推迟行动
or if the attempt had better be postponed.
你给谁写信
To whom are you writing this letter?
居然告诉他我今晚
Which describes the room
要住得房间
in which I intend to sleep tonight.
谁是你的同伙
Who is your confederate?
你的真名是什么 Burnet小姐
What is your real name Miss Burnet?
我叫Durando
My name is Durando.
Durandos 的遗孀
Durandos widow.
[西班牙文]
[Speaking Spanish]
你现在杀了我吧
You can kill me now
我的命没有什么大不了的
what is my life worth
你已经毁了我爱的一切
you have destroyed everything that I love.
你给谁写信
Who are you writing to?
告诉我
Tell me.
你不记得了吗
Don't you remember?
-谁? -他是你害怕的人
-Who? -It's a man you fear.
他在等你呢
He's waiting for you.
他叫Garcia
He's Garcia.
Garcia
Garcia?
[西班牙文]
[Speaking Spanish]
威斯特里亚公寓
Wisteria Lodge,
他要把你送进地狱
he is waiting to dispatch you to hell.
你个魔鬼
You fiend.
我认识这孩子
I knew the boy well.
他父亲曾是我最好的朋友
His father was once my dearest friend.
你谋杀了他
You murdered him.
他背叛了我
He betrayed me
你丈夫也是
and so did your husband.
现在他们派老婆和儿子来了
And now they send the wives and sons.
你们永远学不乖吗?
Will you never learn?
我是不会被打败的
I am indestructible.
开始他们打算
At first they were of a mind
把他引进房子里
to let him into the house
再把他当作盗窃犯杀死
and kill him as a detected burglar
但他们害怕之后的问讯
but they feared the inquiry
会向公众暴露他们的身份
might publicly expose them.
[西班牙文]
[Speaking Spanish]
Garcia 正义会得到伸张的
Garcia, some day justice will come.
就像明天太阳
That is as certain
定会升起一样
as the rise of tomorrow's sun.
我肯定
I have no doubt that my life too
我也是命悬一线
hung in the balance.
大部分时间我被关在房里
Most of the time I was confined to my room.
受到最残酷的虐待
Terrorized by the most horrible threats
来摧残我的精神
to break my spirit.
偶尔吃了他们下药的食物之后
Occasionally I was allowed out
他们也放我出来
but only when they had first drugged my food
我就像你们在车站找到我时
and it was at this state
那个样子
that you found me at the station.
很感谢这位好人
And thanks to this good man
我永远脱离了他们的魔爪
I am beyond their power forever.
好了警长
Well Inspector,
侦查工作结束了
our police work is done
法律程序才刚刚开始
but our legal work begins.
是的 福尔摩斯先生 是的
Exactly, Mr. Holmes, yes.
Garcia的死
Garcia's death
若一个经验老到的律师
in the hands of a portable lawyer
会把谋杀说成正当防卫
could look like an act of self-defense.
但我认为法律不至于这样吧
But I think better of the law than that.
正当防卫是一回事
Self-defense is one thing
但是冷血地怀着蓄意谋杀的目的
but to entice a man in cold-blood
去诱骗别人又是另一回事了
with the object of murdering him is another.
不管那个人会给你造成什么危险
Whatever danger you fear from him.
我想我们会看到正义得到伸张的
I think we shall justice done at the next
我想你把那个混血儿放了吧
I thought you had released the mulatto.
是的先生 他又是个自由人了
Yes sir, he's a free man again.
你的人跟着逃亡者上火车了么
And your man is with the fugitives on the train?
是的 先生 而且我已经给苏格兰场打电话了
He is, sir, yes, and I've wired Scotland Yard
他们会派人在滑铁卢车站
to have their men at Waterloo Station
等着他们的
to receive them, yes.
我必须要祝贺你 警长
You know I really must congratulate, Inspector.
无意冒犯 允许我这么说 您的能力
Your powers, if I may so, without offense,
比您的职场运气强
are superior to your opportunities.
没错 福尔摩斯先生
Your right, Mr. Holmes.
在我们蜗居的这个省份
In the province as we stagnate
这样一件案子会给人带来机会
a case like this gives a man a chance.
-==http://www.1000fr.com== 謦灵风软影视论坛荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业用途
welcome to www.1000fr.com